Earlier on, we talked about the idea of an assignment statement,
之前 我们讨论了赋值语句这一概念
like for example any equals turtle.Turtle.
例如 amy = turtle.Turtle()
It takes whatever's on the right hand side of
它会将等号右侧的任何内容
the equals sign and it assigns it to the variable that's named on the left.
赋值给左侧命名的变量
In this case, the code on the right creates
在此视频中 右侧的代码新建了一个 turtle 对象
a new turtle object and this turtle object gets assigned to the variable named amy.
并将此 turtle 对象赋值给称为 amy 的变量
But we don't have to limit ourselves to Turtle objects,
但是并非仅限于 turtle 对象
we can assign other things to variables too.
我们也可以向变量分配其他对象
For example, this statement assigns
例如 这个语句
the string yellow to a variable called a pretty color.
将字符串 yellow 分配给称为 pretty_color 的变量
Let's see how we might use something like this.
我们来看看如何使用这样的代码
Here's our familiar code that has the turtle "Draw a yellow square."
这是我们熟悉的代码 要求 turtle 画一个黄色方形
Only we'll change it a little by adding this assignment statement right here.
但是我们将稍加修改 在这里添加一个赋值语句
Now that we've assigned the string yellow to this pretty color variable,
我们已经将字符串 yellow 赋值给这个 pretty_color 变量
we can use that variable any place in the code where we need that string.
我们可以在代码中任何所需的位置使用该变量
So, instead of putting yellow here on this line,
因此在这行 我们可以将 yellow
we can put pretty color instead.
替换成 pretty_color
That will have exactly the same effect.
效果完全一样
The turtle will draw a yellow square.
turtle 将画一个黄色方形
One of the nice things but doing it this way is
这么操作的好处之一是
that we can use that variable in multiple places.
我们可以在多个位置使用该变量
Like if we also had some other turtles drawing some other shapes,
例如让其他 turtle 绘制其他形状
we could use the same pretty color
我们可以使用相同的 pretty_color 变量
variable to set the color that they're drawing as well.
设置这些 turtle 所绘制图形的颜色
Then if we decided that we didn't think yellow was such a pretty color after all,
如果我们觉得黄色并不是很漂亮的颜色
we could change the string that's assigned to the variable.
可以更改赋值给该变量的字符串
Like, let's say that now instead of assigning the string yellow,
例如 现在将该赋值字符串 yellow
we'll assign the string, light blue.
更改为 lightblue
So now this name pretty color will refer to the string light blue instead.
因此同一名称 pretty_color 将指代字符串 lightblue
The nice thing is that we only have to modify this variable in this one spot,
好处是我们只需在这一个位置修改此变量
but this string will be getting used in all of these different places.
但是将在所有这些不同的位置使用此字符串
So all of these turtles are now drawing in light blue.
因此所有这些 turtle 会绘制浅蓝色的图形